Carl Damey

Full-Stack Software Engineer · (253) 389-5953 · <u>carldamey@gmail.com</u> <u>carldamey.com</u> · <u>linkedin.com/in/carldamey</u> · <u>github.com/carldamey</u>

I am a **full-stack software engineer**, with **over five years** in the tech industry, including **software development**, **networking**, **cybersecurity**, **IT**, and **tech repair**. My background in both **logistics** and tech has granted me great **analytical** skills as well as those in **optimization** in systems of all kinds. I employ these skills daily to implement **out-of-the-box**, **clean**, and **efficient** solutions to all aspects of software development.

SKILLS:

Languages - C#, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL **Libraries and Frameworks** - React (class-based and hooks), Express.js, Django, Jquery

Database - SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose

Other - IT, Automation, Logistics, RESTful Routing, JSON API, Bootstrap, Server Administration, Linux, Virtualization, Networking Hardware & Software, Training & Instructing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER. CALIBERALPHA | REMOTE

2023 - PRESENT

- Develop and maintain responsive and user-friendly web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Implement modern frameworks such as React to create dynamic and interactive web interfaces
- Utilize server-side technologies such as **Node.j**s to handle back-end logic and **database** integration
- Design and optimize MongoDB databases to ensure efficient data storage and retrieval

INTERN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MENTOR, CODETHEDREAM | REMOTE

2023 - PRESENT

- **Mentor** and provide guidance to a diverse group focusing on immigrants and low-income individuals in a non-profit setting
- Develop and deliver a comprehensive curriculum and lesson plans tailored to the unique needs and backgrounds of students, fostering an inclusive and supportive environment
- Conduct one-on-one and group **coding sessions**, actively assisting learners in fundamental programming concepts and problem-solving techniques

IT SUPPORT & LOGISTICS, AMAZON VIA TES USA | SEATTLE, WA

2022 - 2023

- Implemented efficiency solutions for company-wide logistics software in collaboration with the inventory team
- Created and modified several aspects of the company's **automation** system, learning those technologies in the process
- Obtained skills in **logistics** and **optimization** of systems
- Sustained prompt inventory **processing** and **management**
- **Installed**, **transported**, and **collected** IT equipment for a Seattle-based tech company valued in the top 5 companies by market cap globally

OWNER, BUG'S ELECTRONICS (SOLE PROPRIETORSHIP) | SPANAWAY, WA

2022 - PRESENT

INTELLIGENCE ANALYST (35F), US ARMY BCT | FORT SILL, OK

2021

COMPUTER REPAIR TECHNICIAN, INFOTECH SYSTEMS | FEDERAL WAY, WA

2019 -2020

EDUCATION:

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | SEATTLE, WA | 2023

Software Engineering Immersive

CLOVER PARK TECHNICAL COLLEGE | LAKEWOOD, WA | 2019 - 2023

Computer Networking & Cybersecurity

CERTIFICATIONS / AWARDS:

GA Software Engineering Diploma - 2023 | CompTIA A+ - 2023 | CPTC Dean's List - 2022 | Microsoft Office Specialist - 2017